<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!--
    Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
    contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
    this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
    The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
    (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
    the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
-->

<document>

<properties>
  <title>Apache JSPWiki</title>
  <author email="jspwiki-dev@incubator.apache.org">JSPWiki Developer Team</author>
</properties>

<body>

  <section name="Welcome to Apache JSPWiki">

    <p>
       <img src="images/jspwiki_logo_s.png" align="left" valign="top"/>Apache JSPWiki is the apachified version of JSPWiki, a leading open source
       wiki engine.  It is currently ongoing a transformation from an LGPL project to an Apache project
       within the protective sheets of Apache Incubator.
    </p>

  </section>

  <section name="Disclaimer">

    <p>
       Apache JSPWiki is an effort undergoing incubation at The Apache Software
       Foundation (ASF), sponsored by the Apache Incubator.
    </p>
    <p>
       Incubation is required of all newly accepted projects until a further
       review indicates that the infrastructure, communications, and decision
       making process have stabilized in a manner consistent with other successful
       ASF projects. While incubation status is not necessarily a reflection of
       the completeness or stability of the code, it does indicate that the
       project has yet to be fully endorsed by the ASF.
    </p>

  </section>

<section name="Project Status">
<p>
       23-Jan-2012: The previous attempt to graduate to an ASF top-level project did not succeed for various reasons.
       A new effort is started to graduate with a 2.9 codebase (based on 2.8), so no JCR backend and no Stripes, but the traditional JSPWiki, the progress can still be followed at our <a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?reset=true&amp;mode=hide&amp;sorter/order=DESC&amp;sorter/field=priority&amp;resolution=-1&amp;pid=12310732&amp;fixfor=12313986">JIRA issue tracker</a>.
</p>
    <p>
       24-May-2009: We started an effort to graduate to an ASF top-level project, the progress can be followed at our <a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?reset=true&amp;mode=hide&amp;sorter/order=DESC&amp;sorter/field=priority&amp;resolution=-1&amp;pid=12310732&amp;fixfor=12313986">JIRA issue tracker</a>.
    </p>
    <p>
       24-Apr-2009: Well, it seems that it took a few more weeks to actually make the release -
       and we ain't there yet.  But Harry Metske and Florian Holeczek joined the PPMC, which is
       of course good news.
    </p>
    <p>
       29-Jun-2008: JSPWiki trunk is now completely Apache-licensed, and we're looking to
       have an incubator release in a few weeks.  Also, Harry Metske joins us as a committer.
    </p>
    <p>
       JSPWiki project also has an infrequently updated <a href="http://blog.jspwiki.org">weblog</a> and a <a href="http://twitter.com/jspwiki">Twitter page</a>.
    </p>

</section>

<section name="How to Help?">

    <p>
		Please join the <a href="http://www.jspwiki.org/wiki/JSPWikiMailingLists">jspwiki mailing lists</a> if you want to help us out.
    </p>
    <p>
        We are currently in the need of testers and documentation maintainers, so even if you're
        not a coder, you could help us in a number of ways!
    </p>

</section>

<section name="More information">
    <p>
    You can find more information about JSPWiki from our <a href="http://www.jspwiki.org/">current
    web site</a>, until we get around to putting more information here.
    </p>
    <p>
    We also have a number of ASF web sites set up already:
    </p>
    <ul>
    	<li><a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JSPWIKI">JIRA issue tracker</a></li>
    	<li><a href="http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/incubator-jspwiki-dev/">jspwiki-dev mailing list</a> - THE place for developers</li>
    	<li><a href="http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/incubator-jspwiki-user/">jspwiki-user mailing list</a> - if you're just a user and fear geek-talk</li>
    </ul>
</section>
</body>
</document>
